You probably noticed,
你们可能注意到了，
I put up the here on the, on the my shared screen, the part of the web page,
我在共享屏幕上放的网页部分，
most of the class is driven from the schedule,
大部分课程是跟据课程表的，
I'll talk a little bit later about it,
我稍后再说这件事，
but, you know hopefully you find the url and you found the schedule.
但是，希望你能找到链接，然后找到课程表。
And I'll return to that a little bit later in more detail.
稍后，我会更详细地谈到这个。
Okay, so what's the plan for today.
好的，那么今天的计划是什么。
I'm gonna talk a little bit about, what is it the distributed system.
我会讨论一下，什么是分布式系统。
So what is it,
它是什么，
and maybe get a little bit of info historical context,
或许还有一些背景信息，
you know how distributed systems have developed over the the last couple of decades,
分布式系统在过去几十年里是如何发展的。
then hit a little bit on the course structure, what you should expect,
然后是一些你想知道的课程结构，
then talk what are the main topics or the main recurring topics that we'll see throughout the term.
然后讨论我们在整个学期中会反复出现的主题。
And then we'll see actually the first illustration of those main topics
我们看这些主题中的第一个，
by the case study that was assigned for today, the paper mapreduce,
也就是今天的案例研究， mapreduce 论文，
which is also the topic of the first lab
这也是第一个实验的主题，
and you watch the Piazza,
你可以从 Piazza 上看到，
you know we just posted that a lab on piazza, the url,
我们在 Piazza 上发布了一个实验，一个链接，
so you can go and due next next Friday.
你可以去做，直到下周五。
Alright, so let's start with the basics,
好的，让我们从基础开始，
talk a little bit about what is distributed system.
讨论一下什么是分布式系统。
And sort of you know maybe easier to start with a little picture,
可能从一些图片开始会比较容易，
the Internet cloud,
这个是互联网，
you know we have [] connected to, with clients, and maybe servers,
连接很多客户端，也许还有服务器，
maybe you have servers that actually are complete data centers,
可能是完整数据中心的服务器，
clients,
客户端，
and the data centers themselves, you know maybe internally distributed systems,
以及数据中心本身内部是分布式系统，
that are connected by internal networks,
通过内部网络连接，
the data centers themselves might be internal connections,
数据中心本身可能通过内部连接，
you know outside of the Internet,
在互联网之外，
that servers, a large collection of computers connected by networks,
很多计算机通过网络连接，
and you know sort of informally you know the way I think about it,
从非正式的角度来说，我认为它是，
what a distributed system is
分布式系统是，
as a multiple you know more than one computer networked,
多个计算机通过网络连接，
you know, so they can interact only through sending or receiving packets,
所以它们只能通过发送或接收数据包进行交互，
as opposed to say a multi-processor,
而不是多处理器，
where you can interact from share memory,
那里可以通过共享内存来做交互，
and they're cooperating to deliver some service.
它们合作来提供一些服务。
Those are the four key words,
这是四个关键词，
that define for me distributed systems.
定义了分布式系统。
Often, you know you might not be aware the interactivity of the distributed system,
通常，你可能没有意识到分布式系统的交互性，
you know you might be using some clients,
你可能在使用一些客户端，
for example the Zoom client,
比如， Zoom 客户端，
but at the back end of the Zoom client,
但是在 Zoom 客户端的背后，
you know there are huge data centers or multiple data centers
有巨大的数据中心或多个数据中心，
supporting actually this particular distributed application.
来支持这个分布式应用。
And in some ways,
从某些方面来说，
you know we wouldn't be having these Zoom lectures,
我们不会有这些使用 Zoom 的课程，
if there were more in the,
如果有更多，
you know there weren't distributed systems
如果没有分布式系统，
and, so they often perform the backbone of the infrastructure that supports applications.
所以，它们通常作为基础设施的主干，来支持应用程序。
Okay?
好的?
So why are distributed systems interesting
那么为什么分布式系统很有趣，
or you know what, what are the main sort of use cases for distributed systems.
或者分布式系统的主要作用是什么。
And those are broadly speaking,
一般来说，
there are basically four main reasons.
有四个主要原因。
One is to use connect physically separated machines,
一个是用来连接物理上分离的机器，
you know you might have,
你可能有，
we're involved all of us or any of us,
关系到我们所有人，
as we saw in the introduction,
正如我们在简介中看到的，
or in different locations
或者在不同的地方看到的，
and we get you know we're connecting with our laptop or our phone or our iPad,
我们通过笔记本电脑或手机或 iPad
you know to some server,
连接到一些服务器，
that actually sits in a completely different part of the world.
它们可能位于世界上完全不同的地方。
That's probably the [] basic reason why you care about distributed systems,
这可能是你关心分布式系统的基本原因，
because you know just want to have two machines that physically separated in space
因为你有两台在物理空间上分隔的机器，
and you want to connect to them,
你想连接它们，
and once you can connect them,
一旦你把它们连接起来，
that has an additional benefit,
还有一个额外的好处，
that it actually may allow sharing between users.
它可以允许用户之间的共享。
So if you and I can actually connect to the same computer,
所以如果你和我可以连接到同一台计算机，
then actually we can start sharing data,
那么我们就可以共享数据了，
and you know that enables all kinds of you know collaborative possibilities
这使得各种合作成为可能，
and you know what it is, like file sharing,
无论是文件共享，
you know whether it is sharing of screens,
还是共享屏幕，
you know whether it's sharing of computing infrastructure
还是共享计算基础设施，
and it's all enabled,
这些都是可以的，
because we can connect you know to physically separate machines.
因为我们可以连接到物理上分隔的机器。
There are probably a very important reason,
这可能是一个非常重要的原因，
but a couple other really important reasons.
但还有其他几个非常重要的原因。
One is, to another one is to increase capacity, you know through parallelism,
一个是，通过并行来提高性能，
and you know the paper that we assigned for today,
我们今天布置的论文，
what is the topic of the first lab,
第一个实验的主题是什么，
the mapreduce paper,
mapreduce 论文，
there was a good example of that,
是这方面一个很好的示例，
but the other example is
但另一个示例是，
for example there are many many Zoom sessions going on at the same time,
例如有很多 Zoom 的会话同时发生，
you know zoom.com has some support at all,
zoom.com 必须全部支持，
and it requires a lot of computers to basically increase the capacities
它需要大量的计算机来提高性能，
and to support all those in parallel Zoom sessions.
来支持所有这些并行的 Zoom 会话。
Another important reason is to tolerate faults,
另一个重要原因是容忍错误，
so, for example, you know because computers might be physically separated,
因为计算机可能在物理上是分开的，
you know one part can go down,
有一部分可能会宕机，
and hopefully won't affect another part, of the another part of the service,
希望不会影响到另一部分服务，
so that the service can always be delivered,
以便始终能够提供服务，
so you can get high availability,
可以获得高可用性，
we'll see that as a major theme for this class.
我们将把它作为这门课的一个重要主题。
And then the final one is going to be,
然后最后一个是，
you know also sort of takes advantage of a physical separation,
在某种程度上，也是利用了物理上的隔离，
which is going to achieve security,
就是会获得安全性，
for example if you have, you have a very sensitive service,
例如，如果你有一个非常敏感的服务，
the service to manage passwords for your customers,
这个服务用来管理你的客户的密码，
you know for logging to your service,
用来登录到你的服务，
you would like to really guard that one machine,
你肯定想保护那台机器，
then not shared with anybody else,
不与其他任何人分享，
or not share any other application, run any applications on it,
或者不与任何其他程序共享，在它上面运行任何应用程序，
so you have very narrow interface to that machine
所以你对这台机器要有很少的接口，
and it allows you hopefully you get better security,
它让你得到更好的安全性，
because you just have to protect one small interface,
因为你只需要保护一个小的接口，
and so by putting things on separate computers, isolate them,
所以，通过把东西放在不同的计算机上，进行隔离，
you know you might actually be able to,
你可能会得到，
it's a good stepping stone to get security.
这是获得安全性的重要一步。
These are major reasons, main four reasons,
这些是我认为的四个主要原因，
I think why one wants to, why distributed systems are popular.
为什么分布式系统如此流行。
I'm gonna talk a little bit about,
我要稍微讨论一下，
giving a little bit of historical context you know for distributed systems,
给出一些分布式系统的历史背景，
and where the [] came from,
[]从哪里来，
and what happened over the, over the decades actually.
以及近几十年来发生了什么。
And you know sort of basically sort of the distributed systems,
基本上分布式系统是，
as we sort of now look at them or the way we recognize,
就像我们现在看到的或者我们认识到的方式，
they probably started around the same time that local area networks happened,
它们可能是随着局域网出现开始的，
from year you know I think early 80s.
在 80 年代初。
And so for example you would have a campus network at MIT,
比如，在麻省理工学院有一个校园网络，
and connecting for example the workstations, like Athena clusters,
连接到工作站，比如 Athena 集群，
to the Athena servers, like AFS,
连接到 Athena 服务器，比如 AFS ，
and so that was sort of a typical distributed system at that point,
那是一种典型的分布式系统，
AFS also dates from that period of time,
AFS 也可以追溯到那段时间，
of course, you know Internet was there too,
当然，互联网也在那里，
but there was really not sort of large-scale Internet applications,
但当时没有大规模的互联网应用，
the way we you know are using them now,
像我们现在使用它们的方式，
and so the main sort of Internet scale type distributed systems was DNS, the domain name system,
互联网规模的分布式系统主要是 DNS ，即域名服务系统，
we still use
我们仍然在使用，
and basically email.
然后还有电子邮件。
And so when I early in the early days, when I learn distributed systems,
所以在早期，当我学习分布式系统时，
and those are basically the main examples,
这些都是主要的例子，
that we had to discuss.
是我们必须讨论的。
Now things have changed quite dramatically,
现在情况发生了很大的变化，
since the 1980s,
从 20 世纪 80 年代以来，
and the importance of distributed systems has tremendously increased,
分布式系统的重要性大大增加了，
and one you know significant point,
有一点很重要，
it was data centers,
它就是数据中心，
you know the rise of data centers, right, that went along with basically the big websites.
数据中心的兴起，是与大型网站相伴而生的。
And here we're talking sort of the roughly speaking in the 1990s or early 1990s.
我们这里谈论的大概是 20 世纪 90 年代或 90 年代初的情况。
And so what happened basically is that,
所以发生的事情是，
you know somewhere in the late 80s,
在 80 年代末的某个时候，
you know 80s, the government or congress allowed commercial traffic on the Internet,
80 年代，政府或国会允许互联网上的商业行为，
and basically resulted in boom,
然后导致了繁荣，
where you know start getting big websites,
开始有大型网站，
that were supporting large large number of users.
为大量用户提供支持。
And you know the applications from those times,
那些时候的应用程序，
like for example you know web search,
比如，网络搜索，
you know being able to search all the different web pages,
能够搜索所有不同的网页，
that actually were on the on the world wide web,
在万维网上的网页，
you know shopping and.
还有购物和。
And so these applications you know gave rise to two sort of things,
这些应用程序产生了两种情况，
one huge datasets,
一个是巨大的数据集，
you know sort of indexing to support web search,
使用索引来支持网络搜索，
have the index all the web pages on the Internet,
将互联网上的所有网页写入索引，
so that mean like gather crawl all web pages,
这意味着收集爬取所有的网页，
then compute reverse index,
然后计算倒排索引，
and then you could use that for your search engine
然后你可以把它用在搜索引擎上，
and that was sort a tremendous amount of data,
这是海量的数据，
that didn't fit on one computer,
不能放在一台计算机上，
and the amount of computation to actually do the first indexing,
以及执行第一次索引的计算量，
you know there's also too much for the same computer,
对于同一台计算机也太多了，
as a result, you know data centers came about,
所以，数据中心应运而生，
you know companies started,
公司开始，
putting lots and lots of computers in data centers,
将大量的计算机放到数据中心，
so that it can support those kinds of applications,
让它可以支持这种类型的应用程序，
so that's one lot of data.
这是第一个，大量数据。
And the second one is just a lot of users,
第二个是，大量用户，
not uncommon for, you know big upside websites have hundreds of millions of users,
大型网站拥有数亿用户，这并不少见，
and this requires a lot of machines to actually support all those users.
这需要大量的机器来支持所有这些用户。
And so we see tremendous amount of innovation in the period of time,
所以，我们看到在一段时间内有大量的创新，
we're still continuing,
我们还在继续，
and some of the papers that we read, like the mapreduce paper
我们读到的一些论文，比如 mapreduce 论文，
actually sort of started from that period of time.
就是从那段时间开始的。
That whole thing sort of sort of accelerated development accelerated
整个事情加速发展，
with emergence of cloud computing,
随着云计算的出现，
and that early whatever mid late 2000s,
早在 2000 年的中后期，
and so here where we see a move were users or customers,
所以，我们在这里看到的用户或客户，
basically move their computation and data to data centers,
将他们的计算和数据转移到数据中心，
you know and by other people,
还有其他人，
like Amazon Google Microsoft you know you name it,
比如你所知道的亚马逊、谷歌、微软这样的公司，
and so a lot of the computation daily computation of people
所以人们很多日常的计算，
just used run on their desktop or on the laptop,
过去运行在他们桌面或笔记本上的，
just moves inside of the cloud computing,
转到了云计算上，
and application change,
应用程序变更，
all instead of like running an application on your local computer,
不是在本地计算机上运行应用程序，
you run actually the application inside of the cloud.
而是在云上运行应用程序。
And that means you know that these data centers can have to grow further
这意味着这些数据中心可能需要进一步增长，
and support new set of applications,
并支持新的应用程序，
not only that, you know the customers that were outsourcing their computing to cloud computing,
不仅如此，客户将它们的计算转为云计算，
also started to run large websites themselves,
也开始运行自己的大型网站，
and do gigantic computations on themselves,
并且自己进行大量的计算，
you know machine learning a large datasets or any other kind of type of computation,
机器学习有很大的数据集，或任何其他类型的计算，
and so you see is that,
所以你可以看到，
you know the users themselves wanted to build large-scale distributed systems,
用户自己想要建立大规模的分布式系统，
and that means the cloud providers,
这意味着云提供商，
they're starting building a lot of infrastructure,
开始建设大量的基础设施，
to allow other people to scale up you know their distributed systems to a large number of machines,
允许其他人向上扩展他们的分布式系统到大量机器上，
and achieve high parallelism, high performance
实现高并行，高性能，
and store lots of data.
并存储大量数据。
And so as a result, you know the current state is basically that's,
所以，现在的状态是，
you know it's a very active area of research,
这是一个非常活跃的研究领域，
as well as in development.
在发展中也是如此。
In fact, you know so hard, so active,
实际上，这很困难，也很活跃，
that is difficult you know to sort of keep, keep up to date,
跟上发展是很困难的，
there's a lot of developments,
有很多发展，
and you know even in this class,
即使在这门课中，
we're going to spend a full semester in distributed systems,
我们将花费整个学期来学习分布式系统，
we're going to only be able to sort of look at
我们只能看到，
you know a number of small fraction of all the stuff,
所有东西中的一小部分，
all the kind of distributed systems actually that people are building in practice now.
所有人们已经在实践中建立的分布式系统。
One thing that is cool for us,
有一件事对我们来说很酷，
you know as you know the teachers or students who for the distributed systems is that,
对于分布式系统的老师或学生，
the people that build these data center early on,
早期构建这些数据中心的人员，
even though they were building distributed system for their own internal infrastructure,
尽管他们是为自己的内部基础设施建立分布式系统，
they publish papers about it,
他们发表了关于这方面的论文，
and we can read those papers,
我们可以读这些论文，
and so in fact during the semester,
所以在这学期里，
we'll read a number of those papers,
我们会读很多这样的论文，
that were built by people, that really have large-scale distributed system challenges,
是由面临大规模分布式系统的挑战的人们发表的，
and we can see how they were solved and learn from them.
我们可以看到他们是如何解决的，并从中学习。
This accelerated even more with cloud computing,
随着云计算的出现，这一速度进一步加快，
where you know in the early days of data centers,
在数据中心的早期，
many of these services were internal,
这些服务中有许多是内部的，
for you know the you know Microsoft Google or Amazon or Yahoo for themselves,
比如微软、谷歌、亚马逊或雅虎，它们自己，
with the rise of cloud computing,
随着云计算的兴起，
these services became public services that were used by other people,
这些服务变成了其他人使用的公共服务，
and so suddenly there's even more sort of system infrastructure,
所以突然之间，有了更多的系统基础设施，
that is well documented and usable,
有很好的文档和可用性，
and so we can even we will study some of those cases too.
所以我们也会研究其中的一些案例。
So if you look over these four decades,
所以如果你回顾这 40 年，
you know tremendous rise,
这是巨大的涨幅，
you know of the importance of distributed computing,
分布式计算的重要性，
as I said very earlier,
就像我之前说的，
I did my doctoral thesis in distributed systems actually somewhere in the 1980s,
我在 20 世纪 80 年代完成了分布式系统方面的博士论文，
and it was like, it was an important field,
这是一个重要的领域，
but not, it didn't blow me away in terms of significance
在重要性上，它并没有让我大吃一惊，
and and practicality you know sort of limited to more of these [local area clusters].
在实用上，更多局限于这样的局域集群。
Now you know just like completely booming research field and development field.
现在你知道，它在研究领域和发展领域一样蓬勃发展。
Any questions a little bit about the historical context for distributed systems?
关于分布式系统的历史背景，有什么问题吗？
Okay, let me talk a little bit about the challenges,
好的，让我来谈谈这些挑战，
and many of them you're gonna face head on in the labs.
你会在实验里看到它们。
So, so why is it hard,
那么，为什么这么难，
and worth you know basically spending a semester learning about you know distributed systems.
值得花费一个学期来学习。
There's sort of two things that drive you know the complexity and why distributed systems are hard,
有两件事导致分布式系统很难，
one is there are many concurrent part.
一是有很多并发的部分。
These data warehouses,
那些数据仓库，
you know today the computer is gonna run you know ten thousand, hundred thousand computers in parallel,
今天的计算机会并行运行数十万台计算机，
sometimes know all on the same job,
有时候都在同样的工作上，
we've seen that mapreduce paper today,
我们今天看了 mapreduce 论文，
which is like from the early 90s,
是从 90 年代初开始的，
you know 2000 machines trying to work on one single problem,
2000 台机器处理同一个问题，
so there's a lot of concurrent,
所以有很多并发，
you know a lot of concurrent software,
很多并发软件，
a lot of things happening concurrently,
很多事情同时发生，
it's very hard to reason that through,
很难推论出，
like what and and understand why you know things are correct.
理解为什么事情是正确的。
And this is compounded by the fact,
更难的是，
that distributed systems must deal with partial failure,
分布式系统必须处理部分故障，
so, you know one of these machines actually might go down,
这些机器中的一台可能真的会宕机，
but that doesn't mean that the whole [competition] stops,
但这并不意味着整个[比赛]停止，
in fact you know the rest of the machines probably, hopefully can continue running,
其他的机器可能会继续运行，
and maybe you know take over some of the responsibility of the machine that failed.
可能接管发生故障的机器的一些负载。
But this drives you know these two things together, basically drive complexity,
这两件事一起导致了复杂性，
it becomes harder and harder to reason about why you know the system actually is working,
这让理解系统是否正常工作变得越来越困难，
and particularly partial failure makes things very complicated,
尤其是部分故障让事情变得非常复杂，
because one system, one part of the system might think that another part of the system is down,
因为系统的一个部分可能认为系统的另一个部分出现故障，
but it's not really the case,
但事实并非如此，
you know the only thing that might actually happen is that,
有一种可能发生的事情是，
there's a network partition,
有一个网络分区，
and so both sides of the distributed system you know basically keep on computing,
所以分布式系统的两边继续计算，
and maybe interact with you know clients,
可能与客户端交互，
maybe even interact with the same set of clients,
甚至可能与同一组客户端交互，
because the clients can talk to both parts,
因为客户端可以访问两个部分，
but you know the two in a half cannot talk to each other,
但是两部分之间不能互相访问，
and so this, this is a problem known as the split-brain syndrome,
这就是所谓的脑裂，
and that makes you know designing distributed systems and protocols distributed systems are complicated,
这让设计分布式系统协议变得很复杂，
as we'll see.
正如我们将看到的。
So it's really sort of deep intellectual problems here,
所以这是某种深层次的智力问题，
then I find sort of really aspect in terms of challenges,
然后我发现各种挑战的方面，
it's actually tricky to realize the performance benefits,
要实现性能优势是很困难的，
that in principle are possible with distributed systems.
理论上在分布式系统中可能实现的。
So far,
到目前为止，
we've been talking like you want to increase the capacity
我们一直在谈论你想要增加容量，
or you want to run things in parallel,
或者你想要并行运行，
you buy more machines
你购买更多的机器，
or you know buy another data center,
或者购买另一个数据中心，
and you know of course only when the task is complete [] in parallel,
当然，只有任务完全并行，
does that work,
这种方式可行吗，
and often in practice, this is not the case,
通常在实践中，事实并非如此，
and so actually achieving that sort of high throughput,
所以实现这样的高吞吐量，
and throughput scaling with the number of machines,
吞吐量随机器数量的增加而增加，
turns out to be not straightforward at all.
这并不是直截了当的。
Sort of brings me to here next topic,
让我转到下一个话题，
why you takes 6.824
为什么你要选择 6.824 。
You know, so I think for four reasons,
我认为有四个原因，
one it's interesting,
一是很有趣，
it's like hard technical problems,
它是困难的技术问题，
and with very powerful solutions,
有非常强大的解决方案，
so hard problems, but powerful solutions,
问题很困难，但是解决方案很强大，
we'll see you know those solutions you know for the term.
我们会在整个学期看到这些解决方案。
Second reason is you know used in the real world,
第二个原因是，在现实世界中使用，
and there's a normal amount of appetite for people,
人们很希望，
that actually understand and can build distributed systems.
理解并能构建分布式系统。
If you were a grad student or undergrad thinking about research,
如果你是研究生或者考虑研究的本科生，
it's a great area,
这是个很棒的领域，
because it's a very active area of research,
因为这是一个非常活跃的研究领域，
there are still many open problems,
还有许多悬而未决的问题，
and as we go through the semester, will encounter them,
我们会在这学期遇到它们，
so it's a good area for research.
所以这是一个很好的研究领域。
And finally, if you like building things,
最后，如果你喜欢构建东西，
it's sort of a unique style of programming,
这是一种独特的编程风格，
and so, in the case of 6.824,
所以，在 6.824 的情况下，
you're gonna get hands on experience with that,
你会获得实际经验，
by building you know distributed app and distributed systems in the labs,
通过构建实验室中的分布式系统，
and you'll discover it will be,
你会发现它是，
one it's hard to get them right,
一是很难把它们弄对，
and you know it builds up another skill, type of skill of programming,
它建立了另一种编程技巧类型，
that you might not have done in the past.
那些在过去可能做不到的事情。
Let me pause for a second here and see if there are any questions,
让我在这里暂停一下，看看有没有什么问题，
also feel free to post in the chat,
也可以在聊天中发言，
I'll try to monitor chat,
我会看聊天，
if there are questions there,
如果有什么问题，
or you raise your hands,
或者有人举手，
if you have any questions,
如果你有任何问题，
and I'm sure the TAs will also be paying attention to the raising hands at the chat,
我相信助教们也会注意聊天中的举手，
so in case I miss something,
如果我错过了什么，
you know they'll remind me.
他们会提醒我。
Any questions so far, everything is crystal clear?
到目前为止，任何问题清楚吗？
Oh, interpret the silence is things are crystal clear.
我理解安静就是清楚了。
So let me talk a little bit about the course structure,
让我简单谈谈课程结构，
after this sort of quick introduction to distributed systems.
在对分布式系统进行了快速介绍之后。
So the course structure is as follows,
课程结构如下，
we have lectures like the one today,
我们有像今天这样的讲座，
basically focuses on big ideas,
集中在大的想法上，
the lectures are typically driven by a paper that we'll seen,
讲座通常是由我们看到的论文推动的，
and these papers are often a case study,
这些论文通常是案例研究，
a particular big idea that we're covering in lecture,
是我们在课上会讲到的重要的想法，
and we, the papers are all published or posted on the schedule page,
论文都发布在日程表页面上，
and for most papers,
对于大多数论文，
we ask you to answer a question as well as ask a question,
我们要求你回答一个问题，同时也要问一个问题，
and we'll try to cover those questions or answer during the lecture,
我们试着在讲座中回答这些问题，
and so it's important,
所以重要的是，
you know part of the reason we do that is,
我们这么做的部分原因是，
because we'd like you to read the paper in advance of the lecture,
因为我们想让你在讲座前看一下论文，
so that we can go a little bit deeper into these papers,
这样我们可以更深入地了解这些论文，
so, I strongly encourage you to read them before class.
所以，我强烈建议你们在上课前阅读它们。
Yeah, so another component of the classes, the labs,
课程的另一个组成部分是实验，
the programming labs, there are four of them,
编程实验，一共有四个，
they're split in parts,
它们被分成了几部分，
but four four major ones.
但是四个主要的。
One is the mapreduce lab,
一个是 mapreduce 实验，
that we just posted today and it's due next Friday,
我们今天发布，下周五需要提交，
where you build basically your own mapreduce mapreduce library,
你要构建自己的 mapreduce 库，
as similar to the one that actually described in the paper.
与论文中描述的一致。
Second lab is a lab focuses on replication,
第二个实验是重点在复制的实验，
in the presence of failures and partitioned networks,
在存在故障和分区网络的情况下，
we're going to implement replication, using a protocol that's called raft.
我们使用称为 raft 的协议来实现复制。
And this is a lab that consists of multiple components,
这是一个由多个部分组成的实验，
but at the end of it, you know you have the library,
但到了最后，你有一个库，
that you can use to, what's called you know as you used to build replicated state machines,
可以用来构建复制状态机，
namely replicating state machine or multiple machines,
也就是复制状态机或多台机器，
so that if one of them goes down,
如果其中一个宕机，
one of those machines goes down,
其中一台机器宕机，
then the service actually keeps running,
而服务会继续运行，
and you're gonna use that library to actually build a replicated service,
你将使用这个库构建一个复制服务，
and in fact, you're going to be able to replicated key values service in lab 3.
实际上，你将在实验 3 中构建一个复制键值服务。
And lab 3 is going to basically use multiple machines,
实验 3 中使用多台机器，
you know for fault tolerance, for applications to build one service,
提供容错能力，让应用构建一个服务，
unfortunately you know as well we just see a lot more,
不幸的是，正如我们看到的，
is that just replication doesn't give you more performance,
仅仅使用复制并不能带来更高的性能，
you know because these machines actually have to perform a particular order.
因为这些机器必须按特定的顺序执行，
And so to actually get performance,
所以，为了真正获得性能，
were in lab 4, you can build the sharded key value services,
在实验 4 里，你可以构建分片键值服务，
and that basically consists of many instances of lab 3,
它是由实验 3 中的多个实例组成，
so running concurrently and basically taking care of a part, or a shard of the key value service,
并发运行并负责一个分片的键值服务，
and so that you get parallelism,
这样你会得到并行性，
and so you can actually use this to actually drive throughput,
所以，你可以使用它来提高吞吐量，
and furthermore, we're going to actually move you know keys or key value pairs
另外，我们将移动键或键值对，
from one machine to another machine
从一台机器到另一台机器，
in response to what load changes.
以响应负载变化。
So the labs basically labs 2 3 and 4 built on top of each other,
所以实验 2 3 4 是有递进关系的，
so you have a bug in lab 2,
所以如果你在实验 2 中有一个 bug ，
that might affect you actually in lab 4,
可能会在实验 4 里影响你，
we provide test cases for all of them,
我们为它们三个提供了测试用例，
so all the test cases are public,
所有的测试用例都是公开的，
and we grade you in those test cases,
我们在那些测试案例中给你打分，
so you submit your solution,
所以你提交了解决方案，
we run the same test on our computers,
我们在我们的电脑上做同样的测试，
double-check you know you're passing the test,
复查你是否通过了测试，
and if you pass all the tests, you get full score,
如果你通过了所有的测试，你会得到满分，
it turns out you know these are these test cases are tricky,
这些测试用例是很困难的，
and we'll try to take all kinds of corners in your systems,
我们会尝试检查你的系统中的各个角落，
and so it turns out they are actually reasonable hard to pass,
所以，它们是很难通过的，
and so, and they're tricky to debug,
它们也很难调试，
you might actually happen in particular corner case an error,
你可能会在某个角落发生错误，
and it may be very difficult to track down,
可能很难追踪到，
when does that happen, why does it happen,
什么时候发生的，为什么会发生，
so you know how to fix it,
让你来修复它，
and so my advice to you is to start the labs early,
所以的建议是尽早开始实验，
it's often the case,
通常情况下，
that you know you just start the night or two nights before,
如果你在前一两天开始，
you're going to have difficulty passing all the tests,
你会很难通过所有测试，
because you're gonna get stuck, you know trying to debug one particular aspect,
因为你可能会卡住，调试一个特殊的方面，
and run out of time to basically get the other test cases to work.
就没有时间让其他测试用例正常工作了。
The, there's an optional project,
有一个可选的项目，
so instead of doing lab 4, you can do a project,
除了做实验 4 ，你可以做另一个项目，
and the idea of the project is that,
这个项目的想法是，
you can work together or collaborate with a group of two three students,
你可以和两三个同学组成一组一起工作，
and do a project on your own,
然后做一个你们自己的项目，
and the projects are a former similar type systems,
这些项目是以前的相同类型的系统，
that we read about in the papers,
我们在论文中看到的，
you propose one that you would like to build,
你提出了一个你想要构建的，
we'll give you some feedback,
我们会给你一些反馈，
and we'll tell you, well maybe you should just do lab 4,
我们会告诉你们，也许你应该做实验 4 ，
but if you are excited about doing project,
但如果你对做项目很感兴趣，
we certainly like to stimulate that,
我们当然鼓励这个，
and you should start thinking now,
你现在就应该开始思考，
and then hopefully we can have some discussion,
然后我们能讨论一下，
and settle on something that will be cool to do.
然后选定做些很酷的事。
Okay, finally, the one other component of the course is actually two exams,
好的，最后，这门课程还有两次考试，
one roughly halfway the semester,
一个在期中，
and one in the finals week,
另一个在期末，
and we expect you of course you know to do all the labs,
我们希望你完成所有实验，
and submit read write homework questions for the papers,
提交论文的读写作业，
and do the two exams,
然后还有两次考试，
if you look at the web pages for 6.828, 6.824,
如果你看一下 6.828, 6.824 的网页，
you'll see exactly the balance in terms of grading for the different components,
你会看到不同部分在评分方面的分配，
you know the labs count for most,
实验是最重要的，
the two exams I think are 20 or 30%,
两次考试是 20% 或 30% ，
and then some class participation,
然后还有一些课堂活动，
but the details are on the web page.
但是详情在网页上。
To get you through the semester and help you along,
为了帮你通过这个学期，
we have excellent course staff,
我们有优秀的课程工作人员，
we have 4 TAs,
我们有 4 名助教，
we're running office hours,
我们有办公时间，
and to help you basically get to the labs,
为了帮助你通过实验，
let me do a quick round,
让我来简单[介绍一下]，
maybe the TAs can introduce themselves,
或许助教们可以自我介绍一下，
so you at least know who they are.
你至少知道他们是谁。
Lily, you wanna go first?
Lily ，你想先说吗？
Sure, so I'm Lily, I am a third year grad student in PDOS,
当然，我是 Lily ，我是 PDOS 的三年级研究生，
and Frans is actually my advisor,
Frans 是我的导师，
so I know just how good he is in teaching,
所以我知道他教得有多好，
so you're in for a treat,
所以你们可以学到很多，
yeah, I'm looking forward to working with you this semester,
是的，我很期待这学期和你一起工作，
I'll pass it off to David.
下一个我交给 David 。
Everyone, I'm David,
大家好，我是 David ，
I'm a second semester student,
我是第二学期的学生，
I took 6.824 last Spring,
我在去年春天参加了 6.824 ，
when it was like half in person and half remote,
当时一半是面对面，一半是远程，
so hopefully we can get the best of [] for this semester,
希望这学期我们能得到最好的[]，
I'm excited,
我很兴奋，
yeah, but Jose.
是的，然后是 Jose 。
I'm Jose, I'm a fourth year graduate student,
我是 Jose ，我是四年级研究生，
working on machine learning problems,
致力于解决机器学习问题，
I took this class my first year as a grad student,
我读研究生的第一年上了这门课，
and I really really enjoy it,
我真的很享受它，
so yeah, looking forward to Cel.
是的，接下来是 Cel 。
Yeah, I'm Cel, I used the pronounce,
是的，我是 Cel ，我用这个发音，
I'm a first year master student in PDOS,
我是 PDOS 的第一届硕士研究生，
like some of the others,
像其他人一样，
and I took this class few years back,
几年前我上过这门课，
had a great time taking it,
并且很开心，
so I'm excited to help everyone learn it.
所以我很高兴能帮助大家学习它。
Okay, thank you,
好的，谢谢,
so there's a question in the chat,
在聊天中有一个问题，
how is distributed system, how does distributed system with the lab run,
实验的分布式系统是如何运行的，
is the machine systems simulated,
机器系统是模拟的吗，
yes, we're basically simulating many many machines by running many many different processes,
是的，我们是通过运行许多不同的进程来模拟许多机器，
in fact the labs have their own RPC library,
实际上，这些实验有自己的 RPC 库，
that like pretend you know you're running on separated physical machines,
假装你在不同的物理机器上运行，
but in fact, you're running many many processes on the same machine.
但实际上，你在同一台机器上运行许多许多进程。
Okay, any questions so far,
好的，到目前为止，有什么问题吗，
before I continue into the direction of actually some technical content.
在我继续讨论一些技术内容之前。
Is the, the result of lab 4,
实验 4 的结果，
is it similar to any existing programs that exist?
它与现有的任何程序类似吗？
Yeah, in fact you know what would be building
是的，你要构建的东西，
has a lot of similarity to sort of popular key value services,
与一些流行的键值服务很像，
you know think redis or you know some of the other ones,
比如 redis 或者其他的，
you know there will be differences,
会有不同之处，
as we discovered, when we go through this semester,
当我们在这学期学习的过程中，
but the key value services are pretty well-known,
但键值服务是非常有名的，
and common a service inside of data center,
是数据中心内部的公共服务，
and run by many companies and a couple very popular ones,
很多公司都在运行，其中一些知名公司，
that use with lots of people,
很多人在使用，
and they basically struggle with exactly the same issues
它们都在处理相同的问题，
as you are going to be struggling within the labs,
如同你在实验中处理的问题，
we're going to build one that actually has pretty strong semantics,
我们将构建一个具有相当强语义的应用程序，
something a little bit stronger semantics than some people execution practice,
一些比人们实践中更强的语义，
and we'll discuss why, why that happens too,
我们也会讨论为什么会发生，
but yeah, it's very close to what people do in practice,
但是，是的，这与人们在实践中所做的非常接近，
raft is widely used in practice, for example.
例如， raft 在实践中得到了广泛的应用。
Any other questions?
还有其他问题吗？
Yeah, it's a question about the labs again,
是的，也是关于实验的问题，
if we have a bug on lab 2,
如果我们在实验 2 中有一个 bug ，
that maybe doesn't even get caught by the testers somehow,
可能没有被测试用例发现，
would do we get a like answer to the following labs,
我们会得到一个答案吗，用于后续的实验，
or do we just continue to use our code.
还是我们继续使用我们的代码。
Yeah, you're going to continue using your code,
是的，你将继续使用你的代码，
and we did our best to make the lab, the test as good as possible,
我们尽了最大努力让实验测试尽可能好，
and but I'm sure there are cases that we hard to complete the job,
但我相信有些情况下很难完成这项工作，
and you know every time we discover something we missed,
每次我们发现我们遗漏的东西，
and we basically improve the test,
我们会改进测试，
so you're building, once you pass the test,
所以你构建的，一旦你通过了测试，
we're optimistic that you actually have an implementation,
我们乐观地认为你已经实现了，
that actually can support the other use cases,
可以支持其他用例，
that we're doing the rest of the semester.
我们要学本学期剩余时间所做的。
It's not uncommon for people to rewrite rewrite their implementation once or twice,
人们重写一次或两次的情况并不少见，
as you will see in lab 2 and lab 3,
你将在实验 2 和实验 3 中看到，
you know the structure,
这个结构体，
you have to spend quite a bit of a time
你必须花相当多的时间
thinking about the structure of your application or your library,
来考虑应用程序或库的结构，
and you know as you've learned,
随着你的学习，
that you may want to go back and redo it.
你可能想要回去重新做一次。
To help you along a little bit,
为了帮助你们，
this year we're doing something different than we've done in the past years,
今年我们要做一些与过去几年不同的事情，
I'm going to run a couple of Q&A lectures,
我将举办几场问答讲座，
where I'll share, we'll share our solutions with you,
我们将分享我们的解决方案，
or we'll walk through our solutions,
或者我们将演示我们的解决方案，
and hopefully that will tell you a little bit about,
希望能告诉你一些关于，
you know you can learn from that,
你可以从中学习，
and see how that contrasts with your own solution,
看看与你自己的解决方案有什么不同，
and maybe pick up some ideas for future labs.
或许能为未来的实验获得一些想法。
Any other questions?
还有其他问题吗？
Okay?
好的?
Again, interrupt me at any time,
再说一遍，随时可以打断我，
I'd like to make this more interactive,
我想让它更具互动性，
we'll take probably a couple lectures,
我们可能会上几节课，
but hopefully we'll get there.
但我们能到达那里。
Okay, I want talk a little bit,
好的，我想讨论一下，
you know sort of set ourselves up for the case study for today,
为今天的案例研究做准备，
but before doing that,
但在此之前，
I want to talk a little bit about a bit of perspective for the class,
我想说一下对这门课的一些看法，
our focus in the class is going to be on infrastructure,
我们在这门课的重点将放在基础设施上，
and you can more or less can tell that from the lab,
你可以从实验中或多或少地看出这一点，
that you know were we just discussed,
就是我们刚讨论过的，
and so there's going to be somebody
所以会有人
who's writing applications on these distribute systems,
在这些分布式系统上编写应用程序，
and we're not really concerned too much with the application at all,
我们完全不关心应用程序，
we're going to be mostly concerned with
我们主要关注
the infrastructure that supports these applications,
支持这些应用程序的基础架构，
and the infrastructure falls out in three different categories,
基础设施分为三个不同的类别，
or very broad speaking,
或者非常宽泛地说，
storage infrastructure, like key value servers, file systems, that kind of thing.
存储基础架构，比如键值服务器、文件系统等。
Computation you know frameworks, to actually orchestrate or build a distributed application,
计算框架，用来编排或构建分布式应用程序，
for example again is the classic example is mapreduce,
比如经典的例子是 mapreduce ，
we'll talk about in a second.
我们稍后会谈到。
And then that's the third category is communication,
然后第三类是通信，
and we'll spend less time on communication,
我们在通信上花费更少的时间，
it's almost more topic 6.829 network systems,
它更多是关于 6.829 网络系统的话题，
but it will show up,
但它会出现，
you know in the sense,
从某种意义上说，
you know there's gonna be some contract between the network system and the distributed system,
网络系统和分布式系统之间是有关联的。
and that will be a serious topic,
这是一个重要的话题，
for example first day, we're gonna be talking about remote procedure call RPC,
比如，第一天我们将讨论远程过程调用 RPC ，
and that's like the building block on which all labs are built,
这是所有实验构建的基础，
and that's a communication model,
这是一种通信模式，
and the questions there are,
这里的问题是，
what kind of semantics does actually the RPC system provide,
RPC 系统提供了什么样的语义，
utmost once, exactly once, at least once,
最多一次，恰好一次，至少一次，
and we'll talk about that in Thursday's lecture,
我们将在周四的课程中讨论这一点，
but that's where sort of communication and distributed systems you know intersect.
这就是通信和分布式系统关联的地方。
If you look at these three,
查看这三个种类，
so basically storage, you can store data durably,
存储，可以持久地存储数据，
you know computation to run computations
计算，用来运行计算，
and communication to actually have these different pieces communicate with each other,
通信，用来在不同的部分互相通信，
and so those are the three basic things,
所以这是三个基本的事情，
that sort of, which we build distributed systems.
我们构建分布式系统。
And what we're looking for are sort of abstractions,
我们寻找某种抽象，
that have been proven to be very helpful in building distributed systems,
已被证明对构建分布式系统非常有帮助，
there are abstractions, like like remote procedure call or like mapreduce library,
有些抽象，比如远程过程调用或 mapreduce 库，
or in a storage system, like a key value service.
或者存储系统，比如键值服务。
And often you know often our goal will be,
通常我们的目标是，
to make the abstractions, distributed abstractions
为了使分布式抽象
look very much like you know sort of normal standard sequential abstractions,
看起来非常像普通的标准顺序抽象，
you've made familiar with,
你已经熟悉的，
so for example we build a storage system,
比如，我们构建一个存储系统，
we want our basically distributed storage system
我们希望我们的分布式存储系统
more or less behave like a single machine sequential storage server,
或多或少像单机顺序存储服务器一样，
like your regular file system on your laptop,
像笔记本电脑上的常规文件系统一样，
except you know that you know,
除了，
we hope that the storage system is more fault tolerance,
我们希望存储系统有更强的容错性，
because they use replication,
因为它们使用复制，
may be much more high performance,
可能会有更高的性能，
because it has many many machines,
因为它有很多机器，
like the behavior of the system that we're looking for is similar,
我们要找的系统的行为类似于，
the abstraction that we're looking for is similar to a single one.
我们要找的抽象类似于单个机器。
Turns out in practice actually is very hard to achieve,
但是在实践中是很难做到的，
and you will see that,
你会看到，
it looks like, but it's not exactly,
它看起来像，但不完全是，
and this is a topic that will show up multiple times.
这是一个会多次出现的主题。
In fact, you know that brings me to sort of like the main recurring themes in this class,
实际上，这引出了课上会反复出现的主题，
that we're going to see over and over.
我们会一遍又一遍地看到。
And the main topics are fault tolerance, not surprising,
主要主题是容错，这并不令人惊讶，
and that has sort of two aspects,
这有两个方面，
it's actually to define a little bit what fault tolerance means.
定义一下容错是什么意思。
One is availability,
一个是可用性，
so we're looking at techniques,
所以我们研究技术，
we're gonna be looking at techniques to make a systems highly available,
我们研究使系统高可用的技术，
and so and what we mean that is that,
所以我们的意思是，
they, they continue to deliver their service despite there being failures,
它们在失败的情况下继续提供它们的服务，
and so this is often expressed as a number of 9,
这通常被表示为多个数字 9 ，
0.999 reliability,
0.999 的可靠性，
and so that's gonna be one aspect of fault tolerance.
所以这是容错的一个方面。
The second aspect of fault tolerance, that we care a lot about,
我们关心容错的第二个方面，
these we're going to call recoverability,
我们称为可恢复性，
when the machine crashes or fails,
当机器崩溃或故障时，
we like to bring it back into the system once it reboots,
我们想在它重新启动后返回系统，
you know so that we can keep up the availability,
这样我们可以保持可用性，
because we didn't like repair the system,
因为如果我们不修复系统，
then basically all the machines would down one by one
然后所有的机器都会一个接一个宕机，
until we have zero machines
直到没有机器，
and then we have no service anymore,
然后我们就没有服务了，
so it's important that we repair the distributed system,
所以重要的是我们要修复分布式系统，
the way we repaired to the distributed system is,
我们修复分布式系统的方式是，
basically when the machine comes back up,
在机器重新启动时，
you know we're gonna needs to recover its state,
我们需要恢复它的状态，
and then we're going to start participating back into the distributed systems,
然后我们开始重新参与分布式系统，
and it turns out, there's actually hard,
这实际上很难，
that's a hard aspect.
这是个困难的方面。
And key technique for availability is going to be replication,
可用性的关键技术是复制，
and the key technique that we're going to use for recoverability is
我们用来实现可恢复性的关键技术是，
basically something like logging or transactions,
日志或事务这样的东西，
writing things to durable storage,
将东西写入持久存储器，
so that you know when the power goes out,
这样当电力中断，
but the machine comes back up afterwards,
机器重启之后，
you know were have the data is still there on disk,
数据还在磁盘上，
so that's the fault tolerance side.
这就是容错方面。
The second part is something of called consistency,
第二部分是所谓的一致性，
this is basically the contract,
这个协议是，
you know that the servers is going to provide for operations
服务器对操作提供，
with respective concurrency and failure,
在具有并发性和故障的情况下，
so loosely speaking, you know what we, when we think about consistency,
所以粗略地说，当我们考虑一致性时，
basically the ideal is the same behavior as that a single machine would deliver,
理想的行为是与任何一台机器都提供的行为相同，
so we have a replicated fault tolerant high performance file system setting on many machines,
所以，我们有一个复制的容错高性能文件系统在多台机器上，
would like the behavior to be almost identical to the sequential machine,
它的行为几乎与时序机器相同，
and so the key question which here is sort of the form.
所以这里的关键问题是某种形式。
Let's say we have a key value server does get operation,
假设我们有一个键值服务器做 get 操作，
return the value of the last put,
返回最后一个 put 的值，
and if you run a single machine,
如果你运行一台机器，
and you have nothing you know concurrent operation,
完全没有并发操作，
so you run every operation one by one,
一个接一个地执行操作，
like you do put put put,
比如 put put put ，
then get, then get, then get,
然后 get get get ，
then of course like you know this is this question is trivial to answer,
当然，这个问题很难回答，
you would assume that the get will return the value stored by the last put,
你会假设 get 将返回最后一次 put 存储的值，
but once we have concurrency and with failures,
但是一旦我们有了并发和失败，
and we have many machines,
我们有很多机器，
this is actually not so obvious,
这其实不是非常明显，
you know what the right what the right way, what a good contract is,
什么样的方式，什么样的协议是好的，
and we'll see actually many different contracts,
我们会看到很多不同的协议，
we see ones that have strong consistency,
我们看到一些有很强的一致性，
you know almost behave like a sequential machine,
行为几乎就像一台顺序机器，
or ones that have a very loose guarantees,
或者一些有非常宽松的保证，
and provide very different [],
提供非常不同的[]，
for example they provide eventual consistency,
比如，它们提供最终一致性，
you know eventually you will see a get will return the result of a put,
最终你会看到 get 会返回 put 的结果，
but not immediately.
但不是立即的。
And the reason, there's sort of different types of consistency,
原因是，有不同类型的一致性，
that's directly related to performance,
与性能直接相关，
you know often one of the goals of distributed system is to deliver high performance,
通常分布式系统的目标之一是提供高性能，
you know scale for example with a number of machines,
比如扩展多台机器，
and you know to achieve a performance,
为了实现性能，
that's sort of almost in conflict with you know consistency and fault tolerance,
这与一致性和容错性是冲突的，
you know to actually achieve strong consistency,
为了达到强一致性，
requires communication between the different machines,
需要不同机器之间的通信，
which might actually reduce performance,
这可能会降低性能，
similarly, to achieve fault tolerance,
类似地，为了实现容错，
we need to replicate data,
我们需要复制数据，
means we have to communicate data from one machine to another machine,
意味着我们必须将数据从一台机器传送到另一台机器，
and if we were write, write that machine data also to durable storage,
如果我们将机器数据也写入持久久存储器，
you know that operation is expensive,
这个操作是很昂贵的，
and so the replication cost the performance.
所以，复制会降低性能。
And so achieving these are three things at the same time,
所以，同时实现这些是三件事情，
it turns out to be extremely difficult,
这是非常困难的，
and the fact that people do in practice is,
人们在实践中所做的是，
they make different tradeoffs,
他们做了不同的权衡，
they will sacrifice some consistency to get better performance,
他们牺牲一些一致性来获得更好的性能，
or maybe some fault tolerance that get better performance,
或者（牺牲）一些容错性来获得更好的性能，
and so we'll see, throughout the semester,
所以我们会在整个学期中看到，
a wide spectrum of different types of designs,
很多的不同类型的设计，
that you know make that tradeoff in differently.
用不同的方式进行权衡。
Just a small note of performance,
稍微说明一下性能，
there's two aspects to it,
它有两个方面，
like one is throughput,
一个是吞吐量，
so you buy more machines,
你买更多的机器，
hopefully the throughput scales with the number of machines,
希望吞吐量能随着机器数量的增加而增加，
but there's another sort of part of aspect performance,
但是性能还有另一个方面，
basically much harder to achieve,
基本上很难实现，
which is low latency,
这就是低延迟，
and this is particularly important in these websites,
这一点在一些网站中尤为重要，
where you have thousands of thousand machines,
你有几千台机器，
and you know maybe one user request when you click on a url,
当你点击 url ，会有一个用户请求，
actually costs a lot of these machines to participate,
需要很多这样的机器参与，
and if one of those machines is very slow,
如果其中一台机器非常慢，
you know, maybe it has some mechanical issues,
也许它有一些机械故障，
where maybe the disk is not working a hundred percent,
可能磁盘不是百分之百正常工作，
or some other aspects weren't just really really work well,
或者其他一些方面工作不正常，
that one slow machine can cost the whole user experience to be slow,
一台慢的机器可能会导致整个用户体验变慢，
and this is often referred to as tail latency.
这通常被称为尾部延迟。
And as a concern, that will show up over and over you know throughout the semester,
这个[担心]，会在整个学起不断出现，
as we discuss different machines,
当我们讨论不同的机器时，
and even shows up in the today's paper, the mapreduce paper.
甚至出现在今天的论文中， mapreduce 论文。
So one other final topic that will show a lot,
所以另一个最后的话题会出现很多次，
at least in the class,
至少在课堂上，
particularly the lab is implementation aspects,
特别是实验的实现方面，
and here goes really how to manage you know concurrency,
这就是如何管理并发性，
how to do remote procedure call implementation,
如何实现远程过程调用，
and just building distributed systems by themselves,
自己构建分布式系统，
gonna have actually a serious implementation challenges,
会面临严重的实现挑战，
and that will come over and over and over throughout the semester.
这会在整个学期一遍又一遍地出现。
You know partly it's because,
部分原因是，
we want to achieve performance, consistency and fault tolerance,
我们希望获得性能、一致性和容错性，
and depression crashes crashes in concurrency,
减少并发中的失败，
which makes [disk] drive complexity.
这使得[磁盘]驱动器变得非常复杂。
So those are the main topics,
这些都是主要的话题，
any questions about this part?
对这部分，有什么问题吗？
Okay, then let's sort of dive in,
好的，那我们开始深入研究，
and look at the first case study,
看第一个案例研究，
and through the mapreduce paper.
通过 mapreduce 论文。
And there's an illustration of many of the topics in 6.824,
这是 6.824 中的许多话题的解释，
you know we're gonna be talking about fault tolerance,
我们要讨论容错，
we're going to talk about performance and tail latency,
我们要讨论性能和尾部延迟，
all kinds of issues that actually we see through the semester,
我们在整个学期中会看到的各种问题，
and we'll see one [cut] or one system that deals with that.
我们将看到一个系统来处理这一问题。
So good illustration with many of the topics,
很多话题都很好地说明了这一点，
the paper also very influential,
这篇论文也很有影响力，
although Google internally doesn't use mapreduce described in this paper exactly,
虽然 Google 内部并没有完全使用本文描述的 mapreduce ，
you know they have you know systems directly derived from this mapreduce system,
他们使用从这个 mapreduce 派生的系统，
that they are still using day-to-day,
他们仍然在日常使用，
there are other libraries that look a lot like mapreduce,
还有其他库类似 mapreduce ，
that are widely used,
它们被广泛使用，
and it also inspires different types of computational models than mapreduce itself,
它还启发了 mapreduce 之外的不同类型的计算模型，
and we'll see one or two more later in the semester,
我们会在本学期晚些时候看到一两个，
so hugely influential paper.
所以是很有影响力的论文。
And then finally it is actually the topic of lab 1,
最后，这是实验 1 的话题，
which is another good reason to talk about it.
是讨论它的另一个很好的理由。
Many probably have you have seen the mapreduce paper,
你们中很多人可能已经看过 mapreduce 论文，
shows up in 6.033,
在 6.033 课程中，
if you're an undergrad student at MIT,
如果你是麻省理工的本科生，
otherwise you might have seen in other places,
否则你可能会在其他地方看到，
and, but we're gonna go a little bit deeper than for example 6.033,
但是我们要比 6.033 稍微深入一点，
because you actually have to implement your own mapreduce library,
因为你必须实现自己的 mapreduce 库，
and and as always, when you implement something,
而且和往常一样，当你实现一些东西时，
problems that you know you might not really thought hard about before,
你之前可能不会认真考虑的问题，
you know certainly start popping up.
会突然冒出来。
And so by the end of it,
所以到了最后，
you really understand that mapreduce.
你会真正理解 mapreduce 。
Any questions?
有什么问题吗？
Okay, let me give you a little bit of context you know for this paper,
好的，让我给你一点关于这篇论文的背景，
so this paper is written by you know two engineers from Google,
这篇论文是由 Google 的两位工程师撰写的，
very well-known,
非常有名，
and the context is sort of the early data centers,
背景是早期的数据中心，
Google has a search engine,
Google 有一个搜索引擎，
needed to build reverse index of the world wide web,
需要构建万维网的反向索引，
to basically allow users to query the Internet,
允许用户查询互联网，
and these kind of computations you know take multi-hours to run,
而这些计算要跑好几个小时，
in the you know process terabytes of data,
处理 TB 级别的数据，
multi-hours computations, on terabyte of data, terabytes of data.
多个小时计算，在 TB 级别的数据上。
And so think web indexing web crawling all of this, particularly web indexing,
所以考虑网络索引，网络爬行，特别是网络索引，
so one of the [] application,
其中一个[]应用程序，
in you know as Google you know build these sort of applications internally,
Google 在内部构建这样的应用程序，
you know Sanjay and Jeffrey Dean, you know the two [],
Sanjay 和 Jeffrey Dean ，两个[]，
you know they were very good at that kind of stuff,
他们在这方面很在行，
but they discovered basically,
但他们发现，
there are many other Google engineers
还有许多其他谷歌工程师
who wanted to write those kind of certain types of applications too,
也想要编写这种类型的应用程序，
they wanted to be able to write their own data analysis
他们希望编写自己的数据分析
over all the web pages that had been crawled,
针对所有被爬行的网页，
and so, and they realize you know writing these kinds of applications is difficult,
他们意识到编写这类应用程序是很困难的，
because if you're running multi-hour computation at many many machines,
因为如果你在许多机器上运行多个小时的计算，
it is very likely that one of those machines will crash you know during that computation,
很有可能其中一台机器会在计算过程中崩溃，
and therefore you have to build in some plan for fault tolerance,
所以，你必须制定一些容错计划，
and and you know once you start doing that,
一旦你开始这么做，
basically requires that you basically have taken something like 6.824
就要求你已经掌握了类似 6.824 的课程，
and able to build these kinds of complicated systems,
并且能够构建这种复杂的系统，
and their goal was basically to get out of that sort of dilemma,
他们的目标是走出这种困境，
and make it basically easy for non-experts to write distributed applications.
并使它对非专业人士编写分布式应用程序变得容易。
So that's the motivation for this, for this paper,
这就是这篇论文的动机，
and why you are very excited about it.
以及为什么你对此非常兴奋。
And so the approach they take,
所以他们采取的方法，
that mapreduce take is,
mapreduce 采用的是，
it is not a general purpose library,
它不是一个通用库，
you can't take any application,
你不能接受任何应用程序，
and use mapreduce to actually make it basically fault tolerance,
使用 mapreduce 使其具有容错能力，
and so, it has to be written in a particular style,
它必须写成一种特殊的格式，
namely using these map functions and reduce functions,
也就是使用 map 函数和 reduce 函数，
and those functions are basically functional or stateless,
这些函数是函数式的或无状态的，
and, but those are the programmer writes the sequential code,
但是这些都是程序员编写的顺序代码，
and then hence these two functions, you know the map and the reduce function to sort of the framework,
这两个函数， map 和 reduce 函数是一种框架，
and the framework, the mapreduce framework deals with all the distributed [].
mapreduce 框架处理所有分布式的[]。
So it will arrange that you know the application
它将安排应用程序
or the binary for the programs are run on many machines,
或程序的二进制文件在多台计算机上运行，
or install on machines runs on many machines,
或安装在多台机器上，
and deals with load balancing,
并处理负载平衡，
it deals with certain machines that are slow,
它处理的是某些速度很慢的机器，
it will deal with the machines that crash,
它处理崩溃的机器，
so the application writer [],
所以应用程序编写者，
who wrote the mapreduce function,
编写 mapreduce 函数的人，
don't really have to be concerned about this at all,
根本不必担心这个，
and they basically get all that stuff, if you will transparently.
他们透明地得到了所有东西。
And again to make that happen,
为了实现这一点，
you know the library actually not general purpose,
这个库不是通用的，
so for example you wanted to write a key value service,
比如，您想要编写一个键值服务，
you can use the mapreduce library,
你可以使用 mapreduce 库，
because it's assumes a particular computational model,
因为它假设一种特殊的计算模型，
and your application has to fit in that,
你的应用必须符合这一点，
the computation model you know []
这个计算模型像
you know something that they saw a lot at Google,
他们在 Google 经常看到的一些东西，
which is like people wanted to do big data analysis,
比如人们想要做大数据分析，
on basically all the web pages in the world,
在整个世界的所有网页上，
there are many types of computations that just have to process lots of data
有许多类型的计算需要处理大量数据，
and compute values based on that data.
并根据这些数据计算值。
So that's sort of the type of applications that mapreduce targets.
这就是 mapreduce 的目标应用程序类型。
Any questions about the sort of context and the motivation for this paper?
关于这篇论文的上下文和动机，有什么问题吗？
Okay, let me proceed.
好的，让我继续。
So, let me first draw a sort of an abstract view of what's going on,
所以，让我先画一个抽象视图，
and then we'll dive into more detail.
然后我们将深入探讨更多细节。
So, so you, you sort of need to have in in the background
所以，你需要了解背景，
and understand exactly how mapreduce work,
并理解 mapreduce 是如何工作的，
which is going to be very important for you when you're doing lab 1.
当你在做实验 1 的时候，这是非常重要的。
Is there's a bunch of input files,
这里有一堆输入文件，
you know whatever f1 f2 f3, let's say,
比如 f1 f2 f3 ，
of course, there're going to be many, many more in Google's case,
当然，在 Google 的案例中，会有更多，
but just for pedagogical reasons,
但是只是出于教学上的原因，
you're gonna and size, of the size of my display,
还有我能展示的大小，
I just have three files.
我只有三个文件。
And, basically every, for every file is processed by this map, by map function,
对于每个文件，都是由 map 函数处理的，
so one written by a programmer,
由程序员编写的，
and you know produce some output, so intermediate output,
并产生一些输出，中间输出，
for example the classic example to discuss mapreduce is word count,
比如，讨论 mapreduce 的经典案例是字数统计，
basically counting how many times a word occurs in the dataset,
计算一个词在数据集中出现的次数，
or dataset consists of many many, many files,
或者数据集包含很多文件，
so for example like you know we're running the word count function on file one,
比如，我们正在对文件一运行字数统计函数，
and it will produce for every word a key value pair,
它为每个单词生成键值对，
and the key value pair consists the key with the word and count 1,
键值对包含单词作为键和计数 1 ，
if you know a appeared multiple times in this file f1,
如果 a 在文件 f1 中出现多次，
you know it would be multiple record, multiple key value pairs you know a,1.
它会包含多个键值对 a,1 。
And so maybe you know this file consists of many words
可能这个文件包含很多单词，
going to maybe has a,1 and b,1,
可能会包含 a,1 和 b,1 ，
so the file contains two words,
这个文件包含两个词，
you know similarly,
类似的，
you know the function map function does the same thing for the file f2,
map 函数对文件 f2 做同样的事情，
and will produce some key values,
并产生一些键值对，
and let's say maybe there's only the word b appears in the file once.
假设可能只有 b 这个词在文件中出现了一次。
And maybe you know f3, the map function also runs the file f3,
map 函数也会处理文件 f3 ，
and let's assume,
让我们假设，
let's just where the [] assume that a shows up once,
我们假设 a 只出现了一次，
and you know word c shows up once.
并且词 c 出现一次。
So basically you know these map functions all run in parallel,
所以这些 map 函数都是并行运行的，
completely independent of each other,
彼此完全独立，
and there's no communication between them,
它们之间没有通信，
on their input files,
在它们的输入文件上，
so this is going to give us hopefully high throughput,
所以这将给我们带来高吞吐量，
or you know [] scaled much much bigger datasets,
或者扩展更大的数据集，
and they [produced] on these intermediate values,
他们在这些中间值中产生，
these key value pairs,
这些键值对，
a,1 b,1 you know b,1 alone or a,1 c,2.
a,1 b,1 或者 a,1 c,2 。
And then, so the second step is often referred to as shuffle,
然后，第二步通常称为 shuffle ，
is that basically you know run reduce functions on basically each row.
也就是在每一行上运行 reduce 函数。
So here we got the row all the as,
所以在这里我们得到了所有的一排 a ，
and we're going to run reduce function,
我们将运行 reduce 函数，
and then the reduce function basically takes you know the one key,
reduce 函数使用一个键，
aggregates all the,
聚合所有，
reduce function gets input, the key plus the aggregated values,
reduce 函数获取输入，键加上聚合值，
or aggravate the combined values you know from the different outputs of maps,
聚合从不同 map 中输出的组合值，
so in this case,
所以在这种情况下，
the reduce function would get you know two intermediate results,
reduce 函数会获取两个中间结果，
both a key a and two values 1 and 1.
键 a 和两个值 1 1 。
And in this case, in the case of the word count,
在这种情况下，在字数统计的情况下，
we just add them up,
我们只要把它们加起来，
and so you know it would produce the value,
所以它会产生值，
you know key value pair a,2.
键值对 a,2 。
And we do basically we're doing, and basically what we're doing we're doing,
我们所做的，
we're run reduce for every you know row,
我们对每一行执行 reduce ，
and so this will produce whatever b,2,
所以这会产生 b,2 ，
and then simply on end c,1 for the last one.
然后最后一个是 c,1 。
And again, you know the, once we've done to shuffle,
一旦我们做了 shuffle ，
these reduce functions can totally run independent with each other,
这些 reduce 函数可以完全彼此独立地运行，
you know they can just process whatever row data they have,
它们可以处理任何它们的行数据，
and be done with it,
并且完成它，
and so the only sort of really expensive piece,
所以唯一非常昂贵的部分，
and this is this shuffle in the middle,
是这个中间的 shuffle ，
where the reduce functions need to
reduce 函数需要
obtain you know their inputs from basically every [mapper],
从每个 mapper 获取它们的输入，
so when all the mappers are done,
当所有的 mapper 都完成后，
you know the reduce function basically gets
reduce 函数需要，
you know needs to contact every mapper,
需要联系每个 mapper ，
extract you know the output for,
提取输出，
the output for the map of that particular reduce function
reduce 函数对应的 map 的输出，
and you know sort you know by key,
按照键进行排序，
and then you know basically run the reduce function.
然后运行 reduce 函数。
And so basically we're sort of assuming that,
所以我们假设，
as paper points out,
就像论文指出的那样，
the expensive operation is really,
昂贵的操作是，
the shuffling of data between the mapper and reducer.
在 mapper 和 reducer 之间的 shuffle 数据，
Any questions about this abstract picture?
对于这个抽象图，有什么问题吗？
Okay?
好的？
Sorry I have a question,
抱歉，我有个问题，
so, is there,
那么，是不是，
I know that not all problems can be expressed with in mapreduce stage,
我知道不是所有的问题都可以在 mapreduce 阶段表达出来，
but it is for example like sorting an array,
但是比如数组进行排序，
is it possible to.
有没有可能。
Yeah, yeah, so sorting is one of the applications that they talk a lot actually in the paper,
是的，排序是他们在论文中谈论得最多的应用之一，
and it would be it's something that's totally done with mapreduce,
这是完全由 mapreduce 完成的，
so basically you split input files correct in many things,
你可以将输入文件拆分成很多部分，
the mappers sort their piece,
mapper 对这些部分排序，
and then, they split the output, say like r buckets,
然后，他们拆分输出为 r 个桶，
and then each reduce functions basically sort that particular r bucket,
然后每个 reduce 函数对 r 个桶进行排序，
that gives a total sort of file.
给出一个完整的文件。
I see, okay.
我明白了，好的。
And in this case, you know sort of interesting,
在这种情况下很有趣，
because basically the input, the intermediate values and the output are the same size,
因为输入、中间值和输出的大小相同，
and some other functions, like maybe the map function
其他一些函数，比如 map 函数，
will reduce intermediate state to something much smaller than the input size,
可能会将中间状态减少为比输入尺寸小得多的值，
in the case of sort, that is not the case.
在排序的情况中，不是这种情况。
Okay, let's look at the paper,
好的，我们来看论文，
actually you know get a little bit of sense actually how you [write] them.
让你知道如何编写它们。
Well, see if I can actually.
好的，看我能不能。
That's just annoying, lost my menu.
那太烦人了，我的菜单丢了。
It's hold one second.
稍等一下。
Okay, it's not so cool,
好吧，这不是很好，
give me second to,
给我点时间，
here we go,
在这里，
So we go save.
所以我们保存。
Okay, here the mapreduce.
好的，这里是 mapreduce 。
Okay, can everybody see this?
好的，大家能看到这个吗？
Okay, there's a couple questions,
好的，这里有几个问题，
let me postpone some of these questions,
让我暂且不提这些问题，
for example see them we'll discuss in a second in more detail,
稍后我们会更详细地讨论，
if I don't answer your question, please ask it again.
如果我没有回答你的问题，请再问一遍。
So the first thing I want to do is actually,
所以我想做的第一件事是，
look at one of the examples in the paper of the map and reduce functions,
查看论文中的一个关于 map 和 reduce 函数的示例，
corresponding to the word count example,
对应于字数统计示例，
that would be sort of abstractly discussed.
在某种程度上[抽象地]讨论。
So here's the code for the map and reduce function,
这是 map 和 reduce 函数，
you see that the map function takes key value,
你可以看到 map 函数获取 key value ，
the key is really not important here,
key 在这里并不重要，
it's the document name, so f1 or f2
它是文档名称，比如 f1 或 f2 ，
and string the value is basically the content of the file,
value 字符串是文件的内容，
so all the words that actually appear in the file f1,
所有在文件 f1 中出现的单词，
and it basically goes through,
它是遍历，
you know the pseudo-code goes through the words at the file,
伪代码遍历文件中的单词，
and as an intermediate value,
作为中间值，
emits you know these, a,1 b,1 c,1 etc.
发出这些 a,1 b,1 c,1 等。
Like from the programmer point of view,
从程序员的角度来看，
you don't really see these intermediate key value pairs at all,
根本不会看到这些中间键值对，
you just write this one simple map function.
你只需编写这个简单的 map 函数。
And then, the reduce function is also more or less expected,
然后， reduce 函数大概是这样的，
you know the, it takes two arguments,
它获取两个参数，
you know the key you're like a
比如 key 是 a ，
and values in this case, word count would be 1 1 1 1,
并且在这种情况下，字数统计的 values 是 1 1 1 1 ，
which a number of times that the word a actually showed up in the intermediate output,
是单词 a 在中间输出中出现的次数，
and basically what the function does,
这个函数的作用是，
it just goes over to iterate over the list of values,
它只是遍历 values 列表，
and basically add 1, plus 1, plus 1, plus 1,
然后加 1 ，加 1 ，加 1 ，加 1 ，
and then it's you know the final result.
然后是最终结果。
And so that's basically you know you can see from this code, right,
这是你可以从这段代码中看到的，
like the programmer basically always write,
程序员基本上总是编写，
you know complete straightforward sequential code,
[完整的]简单的顺序代码，
this application very simple, admittedly,
不可否认，这个应用程序非常简单，
but the code for even more complex application would also be straight,
但是更复杂的应用程序的代码也是简单的，
you know, the sequential might be more code,
顺序可能是更多的代码，
but it would be straightforward sequential code.
但它还是简单的顺序代码。
And in this code, the programmer didn't really worry about the fact that at all,
在这段代码中，程序员根本不用担心，
the machines might crash,
机器可能会崩溃，
you know there might be loading balance,
可能会有负载均衡，
that's basically all taking care of the mapreduce library.
这些都是由 mapreduce 库的处理的。
So as and so you know the hope,
所以希望，
and I think this has proven out to be true,
我认为这已经被证明是真的，
is this actually made with lots of lots of people to write distributed applications,
这让很多人编写分布式应用程序，
and process gigantic datasets, and like could no way fit on a single machine,
并处理海量数据集，完全没有办法放在一台机器上，
like for example, the whole world wide web.
比如，整个万维网。
Does that make sense,
这能理解吗，
in terms of you know what the programmer actually sees.
关于程序员能看到什么。
Okay, let's talk a little bit about the implementation.
好的，让我们来谈谈实现的问题。
So I'm using the diagram here from the paper,
我用的是论文上的这个图表，
so the, so we've got the user program,
我们有了用户程序，
so the user program is like the map and the reduce function that we just saw,
用户程序就像我们刚才看到的 map 和 reduce 函数，
you submit the map and reduce function to the,
你把 map 和 reduce 函数提交给，
you link it with the mapreduce library, and then forms binary,
你链接它与 mapreduce 库，形成二进制文件，
and then you give this to the Google job scheduler,
然后把这个交给 Google 作业调度器，
and it will basically find a whole bunch of machines,
它会找到很多机器，
and run what they call workers there,
在那里运行他们称为 worker 的东西，
so like you know scheduler will,
调度器将会，
for example in the evaluation as we'll see in a second,
比如在我们稍后会看到评估中，
you know there are about 1800 machines,
这里大约有 1800 台机器，
on these 1800 machines,
在这 1800 台机器上，
you know the scheduler will run worker process,
调度器将运行 worker 进程，
that actually does the actual work,
它会实际来工作，
and evokes you know map and reduce functions when when when appropriate.
并在适当的时候调用 map 和 reduce 函数。
There's one other process that is important,
还有另一个重要的进程，
in the paper they call the master process,
在论文中称为 master 进程，
in the lab called the coordinator,
在实验中称为协调器，
and the coordinator [] orchestrates the workers,
协调器[]编排 workers ，
and hands jobs or maps jobs to them,
把 map 工作交给它们，
so like the terminology,
关于术语，
here is that a complete application is one job, mapreduce job,
下面是一个完整的 mapreduce 作业，
and then reduce, identification of reduce or identification of map is what's called the task.
确定的 reduce 或确定的 map 则称为任务。
So you know basically you know the coordinator will assign files to a particular workers,
所以协调器会把文件分配给特定的 worker ，
and the worker will then invoke the map function on that particular file,
然后， worker 在那个特定文件上调用 map 函数，
and it will produce some intermediate results,
它会产生一些中间结果，
You know here the intermediate results,
这里的中间结果，
those intermediate results are stored on the local disk of the machine,
这些中间结果存储在机器的本地盘上，
that actually runs that particular map function.
实际运行那个 map 函数的机器。
And when you know worker has run completely particular map function,
当 worker 已经完成运行了特定的 map 函数，
basically tells the master, I'm done with that map function,
就会告诉 master ，我完成了 map 函数，
and you know it tells the master where the intermediate results are.
并告诉 master 中间结果在哪里。
Then, at some point, when all the maps are basically done,
然后，当所有 map 都完成时，
you know the coordinator will start running reduce functions,
协调器会开始运行 reduce 函数，
and reduce functions will collect you know the intermediate results from the different mappers,
reduce 函数将收集来自不同 mapper 的中间结果，
from the locations that are specified in the result the record,
从结果记录中指定的位置，
retrieve that data, sorted by key,
获取数据，按键排序，
and then basically reduce run,
然后 reduce 运行，
invoke the reduce function on every key and the list of values,
在每个 key 和 values 列表上调用 reduce 函数，
and that produces an output file,
这会产生一个输出文件，
and that is the you know there's gonna be one output file per reduce function,
每个 reduce 函数有一个输出文件，
and you know you can aggregate the output file,
你可以聚合输出文件，
concatenate the output files to get the final output.
连接输出文件以获得最终输出。
That's sort of the structure,
这就是结构，
the input files live in a global file system, that's called GFS,
输入文件在一个全局文件系统中，称为 GFS ，
Google uses a different global file system now,
Google 现在使用的是不同的全球文件系统，
but you know the paper uses GFS,
但这个论文使用的是 GFS ，
we'll actually read about GFS next week,
我们下周会看 GFS 的内容，
and the output files also going to GFS,
输出文件也会发送到 GFS ，
the intermediate files don't, are not stored in GFS,
中间文件不保存在 GFS 中，
that are stored on local machines, where the worker is run.
它们存储在 worker 运行的本地机器上。
Any questions about the sort of rough scheduler of implementation?
关于调度器的粗略实现，有什么问题吗？
I have a question about the process [file] for the remote read,
我有一个关于远程读取文件的问题，
so in the remote read process,
在远程读取进程中，
is the file actually actually transferred to the reducer?
文件是否会传输到 reducer ？
Yes, so the, exactly, the,
是的，
so the intermediate results are produced or stored
中间结果生成或存储在
on the disk of machine that runs the mapper, with that map function
运行 map 函数的机器的磁盘上，
and the reduce goes out,
然后 reduce 出来，
and basically fetches it's you know set of keys from every mapper.
从每个 mapper 获取 key 的集合。
And so at that point, you know the data is transferred across the network,
在这里，数据是通过网络传输的，
so the network communication that happens is here,
所以网络通信发生在这里，
the reason that there's little network communication,
这里很少有网络通信，
no network communication here at all,
完全没有网络通信的原因，
is because the workers,
是因为 worker ，
the way the coordinator assigns files to workers is basically,
协调器给 worker 分配文件的方式是，
the worker is run on the same machine,
worker 在同一台机器上运行，
so every machine runs both worker process and a GFS process,
每台机器都同时运行 worker 进程和 GFS 进程，
and the workers are basically send to,
worker 发送，
or the map function run on a machine that actually has that file locally stored in GFS,
map 函数运行在文件存储在 GFS 的机器上，
and so basically this actually corresponds to basically local reads
这相当于本地读取，
you know through GFS to local disk,
通过 GFS 到本地磁盘，
and then the files are produced or map are produced into intermediate files
然后文件产生或 map 产生中间文件
are stored on local disk too,
也存储在本地磁盘上，
so there's no communication happening in this part of the picture.
所以在图片的这部分没有发生通信。
And then when the reduce functions run,
然后当 reduce 函数运行时，
they actually retrieve files across the network,
它们通过网络获取文件，
and then write it out to GFS,
然后写入 GFS ，
there's going to be some network communication here,
这里会有一些网络通信，
when the worker is actually produced the files in the global file system.
当 worker 产生文件到全局文件系统时。
I have another question,
我还有一个问题，
is the, is the coordinator responsible for partitioning the data,
协调器是否负责对数据进行分区，
and putting it on each worker or machine?
并将数据放到每个 worker 或机器上？
No, not really, the basically, the mapreduce run the user program,
不，不是， mapreduce 运行用户程序，
basically saying like I want to run it on f1 f2 f3 f4 whatever,
比如我想在 f1 f2 f3 f4 上运行，
all the input files,
所有这些输入文件，
and those input files live in GFS,
这些输入文件在 GFS 中，
and so as part of the job specification,
作为工作规范的一部分，
usually say which files need to be processed.
通常会说哪些文件需要处理。
Okay.
好的。
Sorry, how does the the sorting work,
抱歉，排序是怎么工作的，
does like who does this sort and how is.
比如谁做排序，怎么做。
The mapreduce library does a little bit of sorting,
mapreduce 库进行的一些排序，
before it hands it off to the mapreduce to the reduce function,
在传递给到 reduce 函数之前，
so, for example the intermediate results might have,
比如，中间结果可能有，
like basically all the intermediate results for keys a b and c go to one worker,
比如所有的中间结果键 a b c 到一个 worker ，
and you know there, you know there's just a whole bunch of key value pairs,
这里有很多键值对，
like a,1 you know b,1 you know whenever a,1 again,
比如 a,1 b,1 另一个 a,1 ，
you know c 1 whatever.
还有 c,1 。
And basically what the mapreduce library does is,
mapreduce 库所做的是，
it sorts first by key,
它首先按键排序，
so first all the as together,
所以首先把所有的 a 放在一起，
and then all the bs together,
然后所有的 b 放在一起，
and then all the cs together,
然后所有的 c 在一起，
and then basically concatenates all the values from one single key,
然后将来自单个键的所有值连接在一起，
and hands that off to the reduce function.
并将其传递给 reduce 函数。
Thank you.
谢谢。
Okay, so I want to talk a little bit about fault tolerance now,
好的，现在我想稍微谈谈容错，
and so go back to.
所以回到。
Could I ask a question about the mapreduce paper real quick?
我可以问一个关于 mapreduce 论文的问题吗？
So is the larger idea the,
一个更大的想法，
a lot of functional programming could be reduced to the mapreduce problem?
很多函数式编程可以归结为 mapreduce 问题？
Yeah.
是的。
Okay, yeah.
好的。
In fact the name hints that,
实际上，这个名字暗示了，
because basically there two you know the notion of map and reduce functions
因为 map 和 reduce 函数的概念，
is something very common in functional programming languages,
在函数式编程语言中非常常见，
and use widely in functional programming languages,
并且在函数式编程语言中广泛使用，
or any sort of functional programming style,
或任何类型的函数式编程风格，
and so the basically you know that's where the inspiration came from.
这就是灵感的来源。
Okay?
好的?
So actually there's a good [] to fault tolerance,
那么现在转到容错性，
because the the idea is that if a worker fails,
这个想法是，如果一个 worker 失败了，
then the coordinators are in charge of noticing that the worker fails,
然后协调器注意到 worker 失败了，
and basically restarts that task,
然后重启那个任务，
and so the coordinator reruns map and reduce functions,
协调器重新运行 map 和 reduce 函数，
Of course, coordinator itself doesn't rerun them,
当然，协调器本身不会重新运行它们，
but basically coordinator to says,
但协调器会说，
you know that particular map function needs to be run again,
那个特定的 map 函数需要再次运行，
because it appears to the coordinator,
因为对协调器来说，
that machine that it handed you know the task to actually is not responding,
它交给任务的机器没有响应，
and so difficult thing is like,
所以困难的事情是，
if the machine doesn't respond to some certain amount of time,
如果机器在一定时间内没有响应，
the coordinators are going to assume that machine crashed
协调器就假设机器崩溃了。
And so, and that means that when another worker becomes free,
这意味着当另一个 worker 空闲时，
and you know was looking for a new task,
在寻找一个新的任务，
and it will hand out the same task,
它会分发相同的任务，
that had actually handed out earlier and handed out again.
之前分发的，然后再次分发。
And so that's sort of the basic plan for fault tolerance is that,
这就是容错的基本方案，
if coordinator doesn't hear about particular,
如果协调器没有收到，
worker reporting back the task is done,
worker 反馈任务已经完成了，
and we'll rerun the task again.
我们将重新运行该任务。
So an instant question is,
所以，立即出现一个问题，
like can a map function, get a map run twice,
map 函数是否可以运行两次，
and even complete twice,
甚至完成两次，
is it possible in this framework,
在这个框架里有没有可能，
that you know a particular map will run twice.
一个特定的 map 会运行两次。
I guess it is,
我想是的，
because if the machine is down,
因为如果机器坏了，
you can't really tell at which point,
你并不能区分是在哪个点，
so how many of the map tasks that it executed,
多少个 map 任务已经执行了，
during the specific mapreduce instance were actually completed,
在 mapreduce 实际完成的过程中，
so you would just have to rerun all of them, I guess.
所以我想你需要重新运行所有任务。
Yeah, yeah, so mostly we just think about this one task at a time,
是的，我们通常一次只考虑这一项任务，
but, so machine like does one task,
比如机器完成一个任务，
then goes back to the coordinator asked for the next task,
然后向协调器请求下一个任务，
and that might be another map task.
这可能是另一个 map 任务。
And so when the coordinater doesn't hear back,
所以当协调器没有收到回应，
it will say, like okay go ask another worker to run that map task too,
它会让另一个 worker 也运行那个 map 任务，
but it could be the case that is you point exactly out,
它可能是你提出的这种情况，
that the first worker the first machine didn't actually crash,
第一台机器实际上并没有崩溃，
just happen to be a network partition
只是碰到了网络分区，
or like the worker coordinator was not able to communicate with the machine,
或者比如协调器不能与机器通信，
but actually it's just running happily and actually doing the map task,
但实际上，它仍然在运行 map 任务，
and it can produce you know an intermediate set of results.
它会产生一组中间结果。
So the same map function can actually exactly run twice,
所以，同一个 map 函数可以运行两次，
and so it's actually one of the reasons you know that map and reduce are functional,
所以 map 和 reduce 是编程式的原因之一，
is because, that's okay,
是因为（这种执行两次的情况）是可以的，
if it's a functional program,
如果它是一个函数是程序，
if you run the same program on the same input,
如果你使用相同的输入上运行相同的程序，
if you run a functional program on the same input,
如果你使用相同的输入上运行函数程序，
it will produce exactly the same output.
它会产生完全相同的输出。
So there's really matter that it runs twice,
所以它运行两次很重要，
you know in both cases were produced exactly the same output,
在这两种情况下，产生的输出是完全相同的，
and so this is where this functional aspect is actually really important,
这就是函数式方面非常重要的地方，
it basically has to be functional or deterministic.
它必须是函数式性的或确定性的。
You see every run of this map function must produce the same output,
每次运行 map 函数都必须产生相同的输出，
because we're going to use one of them into the total total computation.
因为会使用其中的一个到总的计算中。
So similar, can reduce function run twice?
类似的， reduce 函数可以运行两次吗？
Yes, I believe so.
是的，我想是的。
Yep, exactly for the same reason,
是的，出于同样的原因，
I mean the machine runs reduce function is no different than map task,
我的意思是，机器运行 reduce 函数和 map 任务没有什么不同，
there's really no from the fault tolerance perspective,
从容错的角度来看，
there's no really big difference between a map task and a reduce task,
map 任务和 reduce 任务之间并没有太大的区别，
if the machine running the reduce task doesn't report back,
如果运行 reduce 任务的机器没有反馈，
but happens to also will finish the job,
但也完成了工作，
another machine might run, be running exactly the same reduce function,
另一台机器可能也在运行相同的 reduce 函数，
and they will produce output.
它们将产生输出。
Now the only sort of interesting aspect is,
现在有趣的方面是，
this is that both reduce function will write you know an intermediate
这两个 reduced 函数都会写入，
will write the final output file into GFS,
将最终输出文件写入 GFS ，
and if you paid attention to it,
如果你注意到它，
you will notice that what they what they do is actually,
你会注意到它们所做的是，
they first produce the file in an intermediate file in the global file system,
它们首先在全局文件系统中的产生一个中间文件，
and then do an atomic rename,
然后进行原子重命名，
to name, move the file or rename the file into its actually final name,
将文件重命名为实际的最终名称，
and because you know it's atomic,
因为它是原子的，
you know one of the two reduce functions will win,
这两个 reduce 函数中的一个将获胜，
but it doesn't really matter which one wins,
但谁获胜并不重要，
because they're going to produce exactly the same outcome,
因为它们会产生完全相同的结果，
because they're functional.
因为它们是函数式的。
So just to double check,
我想确认一下，
so, if we have a machine that's doing a map task,
如果我们有一台机器正在执行 map 任务，
so a single machine can do like multiple map tasks,
一台机器可以做多个 map 任务，
so let's say that it's doing like 10 map tasks,
假设它正在执行 10 个 map 任务，
and it's in the 7th task,
它在第七个任务中，
and then for some reason it failed,
然后由于某种原因，它失败了，
and then the master knows that this machine failed,
然后 master 知道这台机器失败了，
so then the master will order for all of the 7 map tasks that were completed
然后 master 将安排所有 7 个已经完成的 map 任务，
to be re-executed distributedly,
分布式的重新执行，
maybe on different map machine, so.
可能分散在不同的 map 机器上。
Yep, except, you know it's right,
是的，除了，这是对的，
although I think it generally just goes one map at a time,
虽然我认为它通常一次只有一个 map 函数，
so basically one machine runs one map function or one reduce function not multiple.
所以，基本上一台机器运行一个 map 函数或一个 reduce 函数，而不是多个。
Okay, thank you.
好的，谢谢。
But after the workers done running the map task,
但是在 worker 完成 map 任务后，
does it immediately write it's file somewhere that's visible to other machines,
它是否会直接将其文件写入其他机器可见的位置，
or does it just keep that file in its file system for the time [].
或者它只是将文件保存在文件系统中。
It keeps,
它保存，
map function always produce the results on the local disk,
map 函数总是在本地磁盘上产生结果，
and so it sits in its local file system.
所以它在本地文件系统中。
Right, so then even if you were doing map tasks one at a time,
好的，所以即使你一次只做一个 map 任务，
in the scenario, where you did multiple,
在你做了多次的场景下，
and then the machine crashed, you lose the intermediate work, right.
然后机器崩溃，你会丢失中间的工作，是吗。
No, it's sit in the file system,
不，它位于文件系统中，
so when the machine comes back up,
所以当机器恢复时，
you know maybe the stuff is there.
可能东西就在那里。
Oh, I see.
哦，我明白了。
So the data is actually in store durably.
所以这些数据是持久化保存的。
Oh, I see, okay.
哦，我明白了，好的。
And the map or the reduce function directly talk to
并且 map 或 reduce 函数直接访问
the map functions and the machines are actually have the intermediate results.
包含中间结果的机器。
Okay, so let me talk quickly about a couple other failures,
好的，让我快速谈谈其他几个失败，
and all the questions you're asking great question,
你们问的问题都是很棒的问题，
in fact, that it all will show up,
这一切都会显现出来，
when you're actually implementing what mapreduce,
当你实现 mapreduce 时，
you'll have to decide exactly how you're going to do things.
你必须决定你要怎么做。
So a couple other things,
所以还有其他几件事，
can coordinator fail? I don't think so.
协调器会失败吗？我不这样认为。
That's correct,
没错，
the like your, the cat,
就像，是猫，
the coordinator cannot fail,
协调器不能失败，
so basically when the coordinator fails,
所以当协调器失败时，
the whole job has to be rerun.
整个作业必须重新运行。
You know, in this particular implementation,
在这个特殊的实现中，
they have no plan for failures of coordinator,
他们没有协调器失败的计划，
that's what making the according more fault tolerance is actually a bit more tricky,
这使更强的容错性更困难，
because it's actually a state,
因为它是一种状态，
state that gets modified,
一种被修改的状态，
every time a map function completes or reduce function completes,
每次 map 函数完成或 reduce 函数完成时，
and so it actually turns out to be more complicated,
所以它是更复杂的，
and so basically, this particular library, the coordinator cannot fail.
所以，这个特殊的库，协调器不能失败。
We will see later in semester, techniques,
我们在后面的学期会看到技术，
that we can use to make the coordinator fault tolerant,
我们可以用它来使协调器容错，
if we wanted to,
如果我们愿意，
but they decide not to do so.
但他们决定不这么做。
One reason they decided not to do so is,
他们决定不这么做的一个原因是，
because a single machine,
因为一台机器，
they're hoping basically that,
他们希望，
the single machine that just runs the coordinators unlikely to crash,
运行协调器的那台机器不太会崩溃，
while it's very likely that,
更可能的是，
one of the thousands of machines that run some mapper will crash.
运行 map 程序的数千台机器中的一台很可能会崩溃。
Okay?
好的?
How about slow workers?
那么慢的 worker 呢？
Sort of another type of failure
另一种类型的失败，
to discuss the issue of where machines might be slow,
讨论机器可能会慢的问题，
because like some other computations running on it,
因为在上面运行的其他计算一样，
like GFS is also running on the same machine,
比如 GFS 也在同一台机器上运行，
maybe it actually is using a lot of the cycles or bandwidth,
可能它会使用大量的机器周期或带宽，
or maybe there are like problems with the hardware itself.
或者可能硬件本身的问题。
Is there anything special that they do?
他们有做什么特别的事吗？
I think I recall reading something about,
我想我读过一些关于，
when the job is getting somewhat close to finishing,
当工作接近尾声时，
the coordinator will assign the remaining tasks to additional machines,
协调器将剩余的任务分配给另外的机器，
just in case there are like machines that are lagging,
防止有机器落后的情况，
and then they will take the results that finish first.
然后他们会取先完成的结果。
Yeah, exactly the slower workers are called straggler,
是的，速度慢的 worker 称为 straggler ，
and what they do is like they sort of do backup tasks,
他们所做的是备份任务，
so for example when they're close to,
比如，当他们接近，
indeed you'll see,
实际上，你会看到，
when we go to computation almost done,
当计算快要完成时，
like say there's a handful of reduced task left
比如剩下几个 reduce 任务，
or a handful of map task left,
或者剩下几个 map 任务，
the coordinator actually just basically runs a second instance,
协调器只是运行第二个实例，
or maybe third instance of that task,
或者那个任务的第三个实例，
on a separate machine.
在另一台机器上。
And it's totally okay,
这完全没问题，
that's totally okay to do so, correct,
这样做完全没问题，对吧，
because you know it's functional,
因为它是函数式的，
so it's no problem if we run the same computation several times,
所以我们多次运行相同的计算是没有问题的，
because the it will produce we use exactly the same same output,
因为它产生完全相同的输出，
because it's given the same input,
因为它的输入是相同的，
and the hope is that one of these other guys will finish quickly,
希望这些实例中的一个能很快结束，
and so therefore, then we were not the performance is not limited by the slowest worker,
因此，性能不受制于最慢的 worker ，
but basically the fastest are the ones that got replicated.
而是那些被复制的中最快的。
And so this is only one of issues,
所以这是其中一个问题，
where like basically this is a common idea to deal with stragglers
这是一个应对 straggler 的普遍做法，
to deal with tail latency,
为了处理尾部延迟，
is to try to basically replicate tasks
就是试着复制任务，
and go for the first that finishes.
然后获取第一个完成的。
Okay, I think this is time to wrap up,
好了，我想是时候结束了，
so you can go to other classes,
你可以去上其他的课，
but these are some of the major issues,
但这些是一些主要问题，
that show up in the mapreduce library,
出现在 mapreduce 库中的，
and you will definitely be struggling mostly,
你很可能会艰难地进行，
you know the hard part of actually implemented the mapreduce library
实现 mapreduce 库最困难的部分，
is actually doing the fault tolerance aspects,
是做容错方面的工作，
and but you should keep in mind,
但是你应该记住，
as you're doing that,
当你这样做时，
all the programmers that are using your library or would use your library
所有使用或将要使用你的库的程序员，
don't have to worry about all the distributedness,
不用考虑所有的分布性，
that they would have, you have to deal with.
那些你必须去处理的。
So you're in there unfortunate situation,
所以你处于不幸的情况，
you're not the target of the mapreduce paper,
你不是 mapreduce 论文的目标，
making your life of writing mapreduce application easy,
让你轻松编写 mapreduce 程序，
you're on the that side of the [equation] here,
你在[等式]的另一边，
you actually have to deal with the distributedness
你必须面对这种分布性，
and become an expert.
并成为一名专家。
Okay?
好的?
I'm going to hang around for a little while,
我会在这里一段时间，
so people want to go, feel free to go,
所以如果你们想走，可以随意，
if you want to ask a couple more questions,
如果你想问更多的问题，
you know feel free to do so,
可以随意提问，
and I'll see you on Thursday.
我们星期四再见。